{
  "java": {

    "questions": [{
      "id": 1,
      "question_type": "fib",
      "question": "Java is a ______ Oriented language",
      "answer": "object",
      "hint": "Java works around structures called objects"
    },
      {
        "id": 2,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The correct syntax to print hello world is: A. Print(hello world) B. Print(“Hello world”); C. System.out(“Hello world”); D. System.out.print(“Hello world”)",
        "answer": "D",
        "hint": "You want to call the Systems “out” method and “print” it to the console"
      },
      {
        "id": 3,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "What primitive data structure holds a non-floating point number?",
        "answer": "int",
        "hint": "The primitive for an integer"
      },
      {
        "id": 4,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "When writing a String backslash-____ is an escape sequence for a new line A. u, B. q C. n D. s",
        "answer": "C",
        "hint": "To call a new line, you’d want to use this escape character"
      },
      {
        "id": 5,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Java runs on the Java ____ Machine A. Virtual B. Async C. Old D. Digital",
        "answer": "A",
        "hint": "Java is run using a virtualized machine"
      },
      {
        "id": 6,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "Java was developed at a company called ___ Microsystems",
        "answer": "sun",
        "hint": "Some might say this company rose everyday, much like something in the sky"
      },
      {
        "id": 7,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "A line of java ends with a: A. ; B. > C. // D. =",
        "answer": "A",
        "hint": "You use this when the line is complete, not when its “semi” done"
      },
      {
        "id": 8,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "When a double is converted to an int, it is round in which direction?",
        "answer": "down",
        "hint": "Which way is the ground?"
      },
      {
        "id": 9,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Question: To make a comment in java, you would use: A. <! B. // C. – D. ~",
        "answer": "B",
        "hint": "This would “slash” out the comment"
      },
      {
        "id": 10,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "In a method header, the  ____ keyword indicates that the method will not return anything",
        "answer": "void",
        "hint": "It will return void"
      },
      {
        "id": 11,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "To increment the variable: int i=0; you would use: A. i++; B. I add C. I inc; D. I+2;",
        "answer": "A",
        "hint": "++ adds one to a value"
      },
      {
        "id": 12,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "The modulus operator returns the _____",
        "answer": "remainder",
        "hint": "It is not the Quotient"
      },
      {
        "id": 13,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "A function in Java is referred to as a _____",
        "answer": "method",
        "hint": ": It is a “method” of doing something"
      },
      {
        "id": 14,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Java is a _____ threaded language A. Hard B. Single C. Invisible D. Multi",
        "answer": "D",
        "hint": "Java can use “multi”ple threads"
      },
      {
        "id": 15,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The assignment operator in Java is: A. – B. ~ C. = D. .",
        "answer": "C",
        "hint": "Remember to drink vitamin C"
      },
      {
        "id": 16,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "In java, arrays start an an index of: __",
        "answer": "0",
        "hint": "The number zero"
      },
      {
        "id": 17,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "To multiply two numbers, you would use the __ operator",
        "answer": "*",
        "hint": "It is not “x”"
      },
      {
        "id": 18,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "From the Java Standard Library, you would use the ____ keyword to add it to your project A. Import B. Pkg C. Add D. Library",
        "answer": "A",
        "hint": "You need to import it"
      },
      {
        "id": 19,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "To initialize an array you would declare the type and this operator: A. { } B. [ ] C. < > D. = =",
        "answer": "B",
        "hint": "An array could be kept in a square"
      },
      {
        "id": 20,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "To create a new Java class, you would use the keyword _____",
        "answer": "class",
        "hint": "You may have learned this in class"
      }
    ]
  },

  "golang": {

    "questions": [{
      "id": 1,
      "question_type": "mc",
      "question": "golang question",
      "answer": "D"
    },
      {
        "id": 2,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "another golang question",
        "answer": "another notcoolkid"

      }
    ]
  }
}
